CEDRIC P.-E. MANOUAN

Contact: +250 (0) 791 591 607 | Email: cmanouan@andrew.cmu.edu | Linkedin: Cédric pascal-emmanuel MANOUAN | Github: dric2018

SUMMARY

Software/Machine learning engineer with a focus on deep learning for over 3 years.

Hard-worker with the ability to work independently and with a good team spirit.

Experience in deep learning projects for Natural Language Processing and Computer Vision: end-to-end development from data preparation/exploration to model definition and optimization.

Ability to evolve and work efficiently in a collaborative environment (even remotely).

EDUCATION

Master of Science | *Information Technology - Applied Machine Learning* Carnegie Mellon University

August 2021 – May 2023 Kigali, Rwanda

Master of Science (Semester 7) | *Information Systems and Software engineering* October 2019 – March 2020 Ecole Supérieure Africaine des TIC (ESATIC) Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

Bachelor of Science | *Systems, Computer Networks and Telecommunications* October 2016 – September 2019 Ecole Supérieure Africaine des TIC (ESATIC) - See degree certificate here Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant

Fall 2022

Carnegie Mellon University

Kigali, Rwanda

- Assisting Prof. Bhiksha Raj in 11785 Introduction to Deep Learning
- Research on Remote sensing/earth observation supervised by Dr. Moise Busogi

Software engineering/Data science Intern

May 2021 – July 2021

Zindi

Remote (From Senegal to South Africa)

• Data science competitions preparation

Developer Intern (BSc. end project)

April 2019 – June 2019

Project of Digital Solutions for the opening up of Rural Areas and E-Agriculture (PSNDEA) Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

- Built an Internet of Things (IoT) system for data acquisition in a cassava field
- Developed a REST CRUD API based on NodeJs and MySQL to store data from both sensors and farmers inputs
- Developed a regression model to predict the yield of a given cassava field based on real-time and stored data
- Deployed the machine leaning model to an edge device (Raspbery Pi 3) using tensorflowJS

SKILLS

Languages: French (Native), English (Bilingual, Professional) **Programming**:

- 10**6**-william

- Python
 - * Scientific computation: NumPy
 - * Data visualization: Plotly (interactive), Matplotlib, Seaborn
 - * Data manipulation: Pandas
 - * Machine learning toolkit: Scikit-learn, Lightgbm, Xgboost, Streamlit
 - * **Deep learning toolkit**: PyTorch, Tensorflow/Keras
 - * API development: Flask, FastAPI
- C++
 - * Data structures and Algorithms
- Bash/task automation
- JavaScript

- * Backend development with NodeJS
- HTML/CSS/web development (intermediate)

Document Creation: Microsoft Office, LaTeX, Markdown

Cloud computing / Code management / DevOps: Git, Docker, Amazon Web Services (EC2/ECS)

Operating Systems: Ubuntu, Mac OS

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

Course project - Recommender Systems | CMU-Africa

Fall 2022

Developed a Content-Based Recommender system for scientific papers as part of my mini project

for 04800-B Intro to recommender systems at Carnegie Mellon university-Africa

Project link: CBRS for scientific papers

Data science competition - Image classification | ZINDI

Fall 2020

Developed a machine learning model to classify Tuberculosis and Normal X-Ray images

for an educational purpose

Ranking: 7th/104, Click and look for team DataLabCI on the leaderboard

Project link: Tuberculosis X-Rays classification

Data science competition - Audio classification | ZINDI

Fall 2020

Contributed to the development of a machine learning model to classify audio utterances in Luganda and English from Uganda

Ranking: 7th/255, Click and look for team wakanda on the leaderboard

Project link: GIZ-NLP-Agricultural-Keyword-Spotter

Data science hackathon - Image classification | ZINDI

Fall 2020

Contribued to develop a machine learning model to identify whether a person in an image

is wearing a face mask

Ranking: 3rd, Click and look for team TheCIA on the leadernoard

Project link: Face mask classification

1st prize Hackathon Level 2 (48h) - Image recognition | ESATIC

May 2018

Contributed to the development of a deep learning model to recognize west African bank notes and coins

1st prize Hackathon Level 1 (24h) - Cryptography | ESATIC

May 2017

Contributed to research and writing in C++ the encryption algorithm behind an executable program

HONORS AND AWARDS

Master Card Foundation Scholarship

2021 - 2023

Merit based scholarship to support international study experiences (at Carnegie Mellon University)

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Data Science Club

December 2021 – November 2022

Lead and coordinator

Rwanda, Kigali, CMU-Africa

• Participants recruitment for Zindi UMOJAHACK 2022 (enrolled 30+ new users)

Data Science Côte D'Ivoire

Zindi University ambassador

2020 – Present

Free tutoring for local students/AI enthusiasts

June 2020 – July 2021

Côte d'Ivoire, remote

Côte d'Ivoire, remote

- Participating in competitions and hackathons on the platform (username : _MUFASA_)
- Co-lead of the platform development group (improvements and new ideas)
- Participants recruitment for UMOJAHACK 2021 (enrolled 15+ new users)

Co-founder of the Internet of Things and Artificial Intelligence club

2019

Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

ESATIC